Welcome to another video, so previous videos we have seen some of vlogs, so in this video
we will see the Haciomasa state that we have seen, so that will be used for malicious purpose
most of the time, let us see what was the login is about, I am damn sure guys this knowledge
will be alpha into the knowledge based on the threat analysis, the threat hunting, it will
give enough knowledge to you everything retaining, blue teaming and all ok, so go to the
best, just search for MSHTA.exe, so you can see it will execute dot HTA files, the HTA means
HtML, okay, HtML application host HTA, the MSHTA.exe or that login or all that was responsible
for executing the HTA file, because sometime the threat type will generate a malicious HTA files,
we will see how to generate that and all and he will be trying to execute inside the machine
and he will be taking actual, taking x, okay, and let us start our practical, I am going
to command, so we will generate our HTA pair at first, MSH of venom, dash P tends to pair
our shell, reverse, underscore, TCP and you have to give the L host, my local host IP
will be the one, so you have to give a local host IP that is 18.27, so I am giving
192.168.18.27 here and L port equal to, so if you can use some other ports, you can
you water ports you want, I will just giving the 8654 port, okay, so you can do water port,
it 5, 8 by 43 dash F, HTA dash TSH will generate a name like shell dot HTA, okay, now
the pair has been generated with the 724 zone bytes, let us verify this, yes, it is
all payload, so let us copy the pair in our server directory where www, so we can download
their HTML server, one let us go to the Windows machine, let us download the shell dash
HTA here and we will keep this, okay, let us open this, so you can see it was pointing
to HTML files, so when I give, when I press double click on this, so you can see it
was like executing, it was executing state, if you are giving a run, so it has been executed
right, and there is no remote access because we did not open any of the port, so let us
open our port, LVD, the port number will be 8
543, let us do it now, you can see if I open the Microsoft RHT, HTML application
post, this is called the MSHT process, Microsoft HTML application post, if I click
on the open with MS, sorry Microsoft HTML application post, so now the pair was running,
so now you can see we got a reversal, it was connection, sorry, it is a IP config, so we
got a reverse connection from the target machine, and if I give who am I, okay, who,
I, so he is a user, let us take a privilege, who am I, so he is just a normal user,
you do not have an off privilege, only medium mandatory privilege, he has, so this is
the complete overview of MSHT.exe, you can use the line, you can use the scripts to create
the stable loads, and you can execute in the target machine, and you can see whatever it
was, okay, and let me do one more thing, we will go and investigate what was inside
the script, open with, okay, you edit with notepad.exe, so you can see here, we have some
encrypted payload, we have some encrypted payload here, right, so the payload has been
completely encrypted, and the WSL script and yeah, so that is our